const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In some arteries, the tunica intima is separated from the tunica media by a fenestrated sheet of an elastic material called the internal elastic lamina. This material is most clearly seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Medium sized vein","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Sympathetic heart stimulation is caused by which of the following receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Beta 2 adrenergic receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 3 adrenergic receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 1 adrenergic receptor","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A first-year resident is studying the valvular outlet of the ventricle and is positioned at the infundibulum. This is present at which valve?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrioventricular","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary","bool":true},{"option":"Left atrioventricular","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The aorta is a big vessel arising from the heart. Which of the following is correct regarding the aorta?","answers":[{"option":"Medium muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Large sized artery","bool":true},{"option":"Small artery","bool":false},{"option":"Large sized vein","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriole","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the type of necrosis seen in myocardial infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Gangrenous","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulative","bool":true},{"option":"Caseous","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The left auricle is derived from which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Left sinus horn","bool":false},{"option":"Sinus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"Absorbed pulmonary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbus cordis","bool":false},{"option":"Primitive atrium","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What does the 'v' wave represent in the atrial pressure curve?","answers":[{"option":"End of atrial contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Halfway point of atrial relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Beginning of ventricular contraction","bool":false},{"option":"End of ventricular contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Beginning of atrial contraction","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the best natural antioxidant?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B6","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of these is odd about the structure of an elastic artery?","answers":[{"option":"Presence of fenestrated elastic membrane in tunica media","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of an internal elastic lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of tunica intima","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of pericytes in tunica media","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the main natural antioxidant of the body?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Ergocalciferol","bool":false},{"option":"Beta carotene","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"How long does irreversible cell injury develop after cardiac ischemia?","answers":[{"option":"1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"7-10 days","bool":false},{"option":"20-30 minutes","bool":true},{"option":"24-48 hours","bool":false},{"option":"10 minutes","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which part of the heart causes a delay in impulse transmission?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Bundle branches","bool":false},{"option":"Sinoatrial node","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular node","bool":true},{"option":"Inter nodal fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which creatine kinases are present as biomarkers in cardiac muscles?","answers":[{"option":"MB only","bool":false},{"option":"MM only","bool":false},{"option":"BB only","bool":false},{"option":"MM and BB and MB","bool":false},{"option":"MM and MB only","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following types of epithelium lines the inner surface of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Specialized epitheilium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified cuboidal","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following ions will increase the force of contraction of the heart quantitatively?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Pulmonary artery blood as compared to systemic arterial blood has which of the following attributes?","answers":[{"option":"Has higher pH","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Has greater amount of hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Has more oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Has more carbon dioxide","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What happens to the affinity of hemoglobin for oxygen and the hemoglobin-oxygen curve when blood flows through body tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Hemoglobin affinity for oxygen decreases and the curve shifts to the left","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin affinity for oxygen increases and the curve shifts to the left","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin affinity for oxygen increases and the curve shifts to the right","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin affinity for oxygen decreases and the curve shifts to the right","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Sudden QRS collapse without prior PR lengthening is seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Second degree Mobitz I heart block","bool":false},{"option":"Second degree Mobitz 2 heart block","bool":true},{"option":"Third degree heart block","bool":false},{"option":"AtriaI flutter","bool":false},{"option":"First degree heart block","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the name of anastomosing ridges found in ventricles?","answers":[{"option":"Oblique sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Trabeculae carneae","bool":true},{"option":"Papillary muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Pectinate muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Chordae tendineae","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In which of the following phases, the volume of blood represents the end-diastolic volume of blood?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"During period of ejection","bool":false},{"option":"During isovolumetric relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"During isovolumetric contraction","bool":true},{"option":"During period of filling","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a feature of Wolff-Parkinson-White (WPW) syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Increased sympathetic stimulation of heart","bool":false},{"option":"Increased automaticity","bool":true},{"option":"Increased contractility","bool":false},{"option":"Increased conductivity","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries is accessed via needle puncture for left heart catheterization?","answers":[{"option":"Left external iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right common iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right femoral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Left radial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left femoral artery","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which organism is responsible for the pathogenesis of rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Rickettsia species","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella species","bool":false},{"option":"Coxsackie virus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus A","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The blood moves out of left ventricle by passing through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tricuspid valve","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic valve","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary valve","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the maximum ejection phase of cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Blood leaves the ventricles rapidly to the aorta and the pulmonary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Semilunar valves remain open","bool":false},{"option":"AV valves remain closed","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure in the left ventricle is more than aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricular pressure issues up to 120 mmHg","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What causes cyanosis?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased amount of hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Increased amount of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Increased amount of carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Increased amount of deoxygenated hemoglobin","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Chylomicrons, intermediate-density lipoproteins (IDL), low-density lipoproteins (LDL), very-low-density lipoproteins (VLDL), and high-density lipoproteins (HDL) are all serum lipoproteins. Which of the following is the correct order of these particles from the lowest to the highest density?","answers":[{"option":"IDL, VLDL, LDL, HDL","bool":false},{"option":"HDL, Chylomicrons, LDL, VLDL","bool":false},{"option":"VLDL, IDL, LDL, Chylomicrons","bool":false},{"option":"LDL, HDL, Chylomicrons, VLDL","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons, VLDL, IDL, LDL","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which cells are around and in front of the neural plate, and can be viewed from the dorsal aspect during 3rd week?","answers":[{"option":"Endodermal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Ectodermal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Neuroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioblast","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following morphological changes is seen 4-7 days after myocardial infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Dark discoloration","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"White scar","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow pallor","bool":true},{"option":"Granulation tissue with red border","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is involved in generating the pumping force of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Endocardium","bool":false},{"option":"Papillary muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Epicardium","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardium","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"An electrocardiogram (ECG) of a patient shows a QRS complex that occurs constantly after every 5 medium boxes (each medium box comprising 5 small boxes). What would be his heart rate?","answers":[{"option":"65 beats/min","bool":false},{"option":"60 beats/min","bool":true},{"option":"70 beats/min","bool":false},{"option":"50 beats/min","bool":false},{"option":"55 beats/min","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"When do clinical symptoms of aortic stenosis appear?","answers":[{"option":"4th to 5th decade of life","bool":false},{"option":"5th to 6th decade of life","bool":false},{"option":"3rd to 4th decade of life","bool":false},{"option":"7th to 8th decade of life","bool":true},{"option":"6th to 7th decade of life","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"First heart sound is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Closure of atrioventricular valve","bool":true},{"option":"Closure of semilunar valve","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of aortic valve","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of atrioventricular valve","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of pulmonary valve","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following structures related to the right atrium is inappropriate?","answers":[{"option":"Superior vena cava opening","bool":false},{"option":"Sinus venorum","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus opening","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary veins opening","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vena cava opening","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a non-modifiable risk factor for coronary heart disease?","answers":[{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Genetics","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Rapid opening of which ion channel causes a spike in an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which ion causes action potential plateau in cardiac muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Ca⁺²","bool":true},{"option":"Cl⁻","bool":false},{"option":"Na⁺","bool":false},{"option":"K⁺","bool":false},{"option":"HCO3⁻","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A boy fell from a bicycle and injured his thighs. His femoral artery was damaged. The femoral artery is of which type?","answers":[{"option":"Medium sized muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Falls under the same classification as aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Large sized muscular artery","bool":true},{"option":"Small sized muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"ApoB-100 are surface proteins present on which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"High-density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons","bool":false},{"option":"Low-density lipoprotein and very low-density lipoprotein","bool":true},{"option":"Low-density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Receptors for apo B-100 proteins are primarily present on which of the following organs?","answers":[{"option":"Suprarenal glands","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Gonads","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Defects in which of the following is seen in autosomal dominant hypercholesterolemia?","answers":[{"option":"Apo B-100","bool":true},{"option":"Lipoprotein lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Apo B-48","bool":false},{"option":"Apo C-2","bool":false},{"option":"Apo E-2","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The levels of which of the following are increased in the blood in case of type II-a hyperlipidemia?","answers":[{"option":"Very low-density lipoprotein (VLDL)","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"High-density lipoprotein (HDL)","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate-density lipoprotein (IDL)","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following gives rise to the right common carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Right 3rd aortic arch","bool":true},{"option":"Left 4th aortic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Right 4th aortic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Right 2nd aortic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Left 3rd aortic arch","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Damage to which of the following arteries can lead to anterior wall infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Right marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal branch of circumflex artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior interventricular artery","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of the tetralogy of Fallot?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Overriding of pulmonary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Right ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A \"crisis\" is a Greek word. Which of the following is its meaning?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Danger","bool":false},{"option":"Decision making","bool":false},{"option":"Disaster","bool":true},{"option":"Lethality","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Aschoff bodies are characteristically seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Type-II a hyperlipidemia","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaline atherosclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is another name for stable angina?","answers":[{"option":"Unstable angina","bool":false},{"option":"Crescendo angina","bool":false},{"option":"Typical angina pectoris","bool":true},{"option":"Prinzmetal angina","bool":false},{"option":"Variant angina","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following does not lead to cor pulmonale?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic altitude sickness","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":false},{"option":"Kyphoscoliosis","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Lipoproteins can be separated on the basis of their mobility by which of the following techniques?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Distillation","bool":false},{"option":"Immuno-electrophoresis","bool":false},{"option":"Electrophoresis","bool":true},{"option":"Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Bone marrow, spleen, and liver contain which of the following types of vessels?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sinusoidal capillaries","bool":true},{"option":"Elastic arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Fenestrated capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Continuous capillaries","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following complications can develop after 4-7 days of myocardial infarction as a result of action by macrophages?","answers":[{"option":"Aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiogenic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinous pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac tamponade","bool":true},{"option":"Arrhythmia","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following does not lead to aortic regurgitation?","answers":[{"option":"Marfan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":true},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about Prinzmetal variant angina?","answers":[{"option":"Its anginal attacks are related to physical activity","bool":false},{"option":"It is usually relieved by rest","bool":false},{"option":"It is one of the common forms of episodic myocardial ischemia","bool":false},{"option":"It is caused by coronary artery spasm","bool":true},{"option":"It is caused by disruption of atherosclerotic plaque","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Q wave in a normal electrocardiogram represents which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Net direction of early ventricular depolarization","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial depolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Net direction of early ventricular repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial ischemia","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Pericytes are found in the walls of which of the following vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphatic vessel","bool":false},{"option":"Capillary","bool":true},{"option":"Muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Elastic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vein","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is not found in the right ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Conus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve","bool":true},{"option":"Chordae tendineae","bool":false},{"option":"Supraventricular crest","bool":false},{"option":"Trabeculae carneae","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following layers of the heart contains nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Myocardium","bool":false},{"option":"Sub-endothelial layer","bool":true},{"option":"Sub-epithelial connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial layer","bool":false},{"option":"Epicardium","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In which week do the cardiogenic cells move rostral to the oropharyngeal membrane?","answers":[{"option":"2nd","bool":false},{"option":"4th","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":true},{"option":"1st","bool":false},{"option":"5th","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In case of increased venous return, what will be the effect on the heart according to the Frank-Starling mechanism?","answers":[{"option":"lncrease in end systolic volume","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemia of heart muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased cardiac output","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased contractility","bool":false},{"option":"lncrease in end diastolic volume","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which type of lipid intake is healthy for cardiovascular disease (CVD) patients?","answers":[{"option":"Poly unsaturated","bool":true},{"option":"Monosaturated","bool":false},{"option":"Saturated","bool":false},{"option":"Medium saturated","bool":false},{"option":"Trans saturated","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Elevation in the levels of which of the following amino acids increases the risk of coronary artery disease?","answers":[{"option":"Methionine","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Homocysteine","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is correct about normal electrocardiogram (ECG)?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"T wave represents ventricular depolarization","bool":false},{"option":"QRS complex represents ventricular repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"P wave represents atrial repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Prominent Q waves are absent","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the area of least resistance between cardiac cells?","answers":[{"option":"Fascia adherens","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tight junctions","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Desmosomes","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The heart is able to generate and conduct its own impulses. The impulse generating and conducting system of heart is present in which of the following layers?","answers":[{"option":"Endocardium","bool":true},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardium","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Epicardium","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Right anterior and right common cardinal veins combine to form which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sinus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"Right brachiocephalic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Left brachiocephalic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following type(s) of paroxysmal tachycardia is/are also termed supraventricular tachycardia?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial","bool":false},{"option":"A-V nodal","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial and A-V nodal","bool":true},{"option":"Ventricular","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial and ventricular","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following types of vessels has a smooth muscle layer in between two elastic laminae?","answers":[{"option":"Elastic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medium-sized vein","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriole","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular artery","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Hypertension can lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Polyarteritis nodosa","bool":false},{"option":"Heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral valve prolapse","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following gives rise to right auricle?","answers":[{"option":"Primordial atrium","bool":true},{"option":"Sinus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbus cordis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Truncus arteriosus","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Elevated levels of aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT) indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Liver disease","bool":true},{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In electrocardiogram, the contraction and relaxation of ventricles is represented by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"T wave","bool":false},{"option":"Q wave","bool":false},{"option":"PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"QRS complex","bool":false},{"option":"QT interval","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following bring oxygenated blood to left atrium?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary veins","bool":true},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following metabolite acts as a localized vasodilator?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Increased pH","bool":false},{"option":"Increased oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased carbon dioxide","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common congenital defect of heart?","answers":[{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Transposition of great vessels","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following decreases the cardiac output?","answers":[{"option":"Increased heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in cardiac contraction","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Increased venous return","bool":false},{"option":"Increased atrial natriuretic peptide (ANP)","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following occurs just after the depolarization of atria (P wave)?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial systole","bool":true},{"option":"Rapid ejection","bool":false},{"option":"Iso-volumetric contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Iso-volumetric relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Slow ejection","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is not guarded by a valve in right atrium?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular orifice","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The left border of the heart is mainly formed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is most commonly used in hypertensive emergencies?","answers":[{"option":"Coptopril","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium nitroprusside","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Propanolol","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about cardiac muscle?","answers":[{"option":"It is more similar to smooth muscle","bool":false},{"option":"It can act as a syncytium","bool":true},{"option":"It is not striated","bool":false},{"option":"It doesn‘t  have intercalated disks between its cells","bool":false},{"option":"It doesn't have actin or myosin filaments","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In what condition is antegrade and retrograde of atrioventricular node found?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial flutter","bool":false},{"option":"Junctional rhythm","bool":true},{"option":"Wandering atrial pacemaker","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is true regarding muscular arteries?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Concentric layer of smooth muscles in the media","bool":true},{"option":"Muscular adventitia","bool":false},{"option":"Concentric elastic in the media","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa vasorum in the intima","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which type of fat is beneficial for cardiovascular health?","answers":[{"option":"Omega 11 unsaturated fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Omega 6 unsaturated fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Omega 3 unsaturated fatty acids","bool":true},{"option":"Saturated fatty acids","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a cardioselective beta-1 antagonist?","answers":[{"option":"Atenolol","bool":true},{"option":"Propanolol","bool":false},{"option":"Pindolol","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Nadalol","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"HMG carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Fatty acyl CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG CoA synthase","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A girl is taking an exercise test.  Which of the following will decrease in skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriolar resistance","bool":true},{"option":"Lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic activity","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the ability of a muscle to respond to a stimulus called?","answers":[{"option":"Plasticity","bool":false},{"option":"Excitability","bool":true},{"option":"Rhythmicity","bool":false},{"option":"Conductivity","bool":false},{"option":"Distensibility","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the first sign of heart failure?","answers":[{"option":"Paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Dyspnea and cough","bool":true},{"option":"Orthopnea","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the condition called when the pulmonary artery arises from the left ventricle and the aorta arises from the right ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Teratology of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Transposition of great vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Coarctation of the aorta","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Generation of which potential produces the T-wave?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricles recover from repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Atria recover from sinoatrial nodal delay","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricles recover from depolarization","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial delay at ventricular fiber","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Intermediate-density lipoprotein is formed from very low-density lipoprotein by the removal of which substance?","answers":[{"option":"Fatty acid","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Triacylglycerol","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Protein","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is true regarding fossa ovalis?","answers":[{"option":"Thebesian valves are present","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lies anterior to atrium proper","bool":false},{"option":"Upper border of the fossa is called limbus of fossa ovalis","bool":true},{"option":"Euschtasian valve is present","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What are Aschoff bodies in rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"B lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"T lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Neutrophil","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"To what structure is fibrous pericardium attached?","answers":[{"option":"Left atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Is not attached to any part of the heart","bool":true},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which lipid is mainly found in the atherosclerotic plaque?","answers":[{"option":"High-density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Very low-density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"Low-density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is not true about the superior vena cava?","answers":[{"option":"Has 10 cm length","bool":true},{"option":"Formed by right and left brachiocephalic veins","bool":false},{"option":"Is not separated  from right atrium via any valves","bool":false},{"option":"Receives azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Begins at the first costal cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The strength of contraction of the heart depends on the concentration of which extracellular ion?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium ion","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium ion","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium ion","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium ion","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate ion","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is glycerol-containing phospholipid called?","answers":[{"option":"Sphingosine","bool":false},{"option":"Choline","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycerophospholipid","bool":true},{"option":"Glycerolipid","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following substances is not a vasodilator?","answers":[{"option":"Kinin","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelin","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a deep vein of the lower limb?","answers":[{"option":"External iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral vein","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior tibial vein","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"The anastomosis between the right anterior and left anterior cardinal vein forms which vein?","answers":[{"option":"External iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Popliteal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Digital palmar veins","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic vein","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What causes the delay of impulses from the sinoatrial node to the atrioventricular bundle?","answers":[{"option":"Sinoatrial node","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular fibers","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje system","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular node","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is incorrect regarding lymphatic ducts?","answers":[{"option":"Converge into two large trunks: thoracic duct and the left lymphatic duct","bool":true},{"option":"Same as veins except that veins have more muscle in the media","bool":false},{"option":"Blind tubes","bool":false},{"option":"Contain horizontally and longitudinally running muscle fibers","bool":false},{"option":"The adventitia is poorly defined","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which substance acts as an antioxidant in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Niacin","bool":false},{"option":"Folate","bool":false},{"option":"Tocopherol","bool":true},{"option":"Thymine","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecalciferol","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What are the main stages of crisis intervention?","answers":[{"option":"Assessment, exploration, and agreement","bool":true},{"option":"Agreement only","bool":false},{"option":"Exploration only","bool":false},{"option":"Assessment only","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which valve guides the blood in right to left shunt through foramen ovale?","answers":[{"option":"Cephalic valve","bool":false},{"option":"Thebesian valve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava valve","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid  valve","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the similarity between cardiac and skeletal muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Length of muscle fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Rhythmicity","bool":false},{"option":"Plateau","bool":false},{"option":"Resting membrane potential","bool":true},{"option":"Refractory period","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following causes increased turbulence in blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased density of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased viscosity of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Increased length of vessel","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased diameter of vessel","bool":false},{"option":"Increased velocity of blood","bool":true}]},{"id":109,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"A patient with a history of rheumatic heart disease, now complains of breathlessness and needs workup for valvular heart disease. The suspected diagnosis is mitral valve stenosis. What is the gold standard for the diagnosis of mitral valve stenosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac cathetarization","bool":false},{"option":"Angiography","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiogram","bool":true},{"option":"Electrocardiogram","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a non-nutrient antioxidant?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha hay","bool":false},{"option":"Phytochemicals","bool":true},{"option":"Hormones","bool":false},{"option":"Beta carotene","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following does not affect the turbulence of blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Velocity","bool":false},{"option":"Length","bool":true},{"option":"Viscosity","bool":false},{"option":"Diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Density","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is a secondary disaster?","answers":[{"option":"Disability flashbacks","bool":false},{"option":"Death of loved ones after the end of trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Wound infection, malnutrition, death and disease","bool":false},{"option":"Depression and anxiety after a traumatic event","bool":true},{"option":"Facing situational crisis after developmental crisis","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the stressful time during maturational and transitional period called?","answers":[{"option":"Developmental crises","bool":false},{"option":"Emergency crises","bool":false},{"option":"Situational crises","bool":false},{"option":"Maturational crisis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What occurs just at the start of isovolumetric contraction?","answers":[{"option":"Atrioventricular valves open","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular valves close","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricles contract and there is emptying of ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic valves close","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What does the ‘a’ wave represent in the atrial pressure curve of the cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial dilation","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial failure","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial filling","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is true regarding mitral valve prolapse?","answers":[{"option":"Common in men","bool":false},{"option":"Bulging into ventricle during ventricular systole","bool":false},{"option":"Limited to one leaflet","bool":false},{"option":"Asymptomatic","bool":true},{"option":"Myomatous degeneration and diastolic click","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is an example of secondary prevention for cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Life style modification","bool":false},{"option":"Screening the population at high risk","bool":true},{"option":"Community based approach","bool":false},{"option":"Regular medical checkups","bool":false},{"option":"Exercise","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding both the tricuspid and semilunar valves?","answers":[{"option":"Have two cusps","bool":false},{"option":"Have three cusps","bool":true},{"option":"Produce the first heart sound","bool":false},{"option":"Have tendinous filaments attached","bool":false},{"option":"Produce the second heart sound","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Ductus arteriosus is derived from which pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Seventh","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth","bool":false},{"option":"Second","bool":false},{"option":"Sixth","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which electrical polarization causes the generation of the P wave?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular repolarization before ventricular relaxation","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial repolarization before sinoatrial node contracts","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular depolarization before ventricular contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial depolarization before atrial contraction begins","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial repolarization before atrial contraction begins","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What occurs in the isovolumetric contraction of the ventricles?","answers":[{"option":"Atrioventricular valves are open","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial muscles contract","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricles are filling","bool":false},{"option":"End diastolic volume increases","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricles contract but no emptying occurs","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is the most common cardiac defect?","answers":[{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Transposition of great vessels","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Cholesterol is converted into cholesterol esters in high-density lipoproteins through which enzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Lipoproteinous acetyl CoA transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Lactate acetyl CoA transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosomal acetyl CoA transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Lecithin:cholesterol acyltransferase","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is correct about the right coronary artery?","answers":[{"option":"It arises from the lateral aortic sinus","bool":false},{"option":"It ends by anastomosing with the right marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"It emerges at the surface of the heart between the root of the pulmonary trunk and the right auricle","bool":true},{"option":"It gives nodal artery in 40% of the cases","bool":false},{"option":"It is larger than the left coronary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Sudden closure of which valve produces the second heart sound?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary valve at the beginning of sinoatrial node action potentail","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary valve in the middle of systole","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic valve in the middle of systole","bool":false},{"option":"Semilunar valve at the end of systole","bool":true},{"option":"Semilunar valve at the beginning of systole","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What are the Anitschkow cells in rheumatic disease?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"T cells","bool":false},{"option":"B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true}]},{"id":127,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Calcium is moved to the sarcoplasmic reticulum after contraction by the activity of which pump?","answers":[{"option":"Ca-Na pump","bool":false},{"option":"Na-ATPase pump","bool":false},{"option":"Na pump","bool":false},{"option":"K pump","bool":false},{"option":"Ca-ATPase pump","bool":true}]},{"id":128,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is true regarding foramen ovale?","answers":[{"option":"Closes late after birth, fuses completely within first year, and forms fossa ovalis","bool":false},{"option":"Closes immediately after birth, fuses completely within six months, and forms ligamentum venous","bool":false},{"option":"Remains patent after birth, fuses completely within first year, and forms fossa ovalis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Closes immediately after birth, fuses completely within first year, and forms fossa ovalis","bool":true}]},{"id":129,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Increase in which of the following leads to decreased cardiac output?","answers":[{"option":"Heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":true},{"option":"Blood volume","bool":false},{"option":"Stroke volume","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What is true about pericardium?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous pericardium is continuous with serous pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"It is attached to the sternum by anterior and posterior sternopericardial ligaments","bool":false},{"option":"Serous pericardium is a double-layered structure lined by mesothelium","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrous pericardium is adherent to visceral layer of serous pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which statement is not true regarding vessels in chronic atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Focal thickening  of intima","bool":false},{"option":"Disappearance of adventitia","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in concentric smooth muscles of media","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"What causes secondary renal hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic kidney disease","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Induced pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Intracranial pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"In which condition is fixed PR lengthening seen?","answers":[{"option":"Second degree Mobitz 2 heart block","bool":false},{"option":"Second degree Mobitz I heart block","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Third degree heart block","bool":false},{"option":"First degree heart block","bool":true}]},{"id":134,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Why does high-density lipoprotein have high density?","answers":[{"option":"Highest protein and minimal lipid proportion","bool":true},{"option":"Minimal protein and highest lipid proportion","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal protein and minimal lipid proportion","bool":false},{"option":"Highest protein and highest lipid proportion","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2019","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false}]}]
export default arr